（デイダラ）うっ！
まったく… とっておきの
自爆分身まで食いとられるとはな
Gimme a break...
I wouldn't have thought that
my Self-Destructing Clone
would be eaten away too...
（デイダラ）俺の究極芸術を
見せてやろう
I'll show you my ultimate work of art...
（デイダラ）芸術は爆発だ！
Art is an explosion!
Release!
（デイダラ）喝！
（はたけカカシ）
どうにか間に合ったな
I somehow made it in time...
（デイダラ）まあ あれが陽動になって
なんとか逃げられはしたが
Then again, I managed to flee
because that acted as a diversion...
俺の腕を空間ごと…
なんて術だ！
My arm's getting sucked into space...?!
What a Jutsu!
（ちぎれる音）
（デイダラ）ぐわぁ！
（デイダラ）ふん… 持ってかれたのは
ひじの辺りだけだったな
What I lost was...
only up to about my elbow.
落っことした右手と指輪は
探さねえとな うん
I must search for my right arm and ring...
（黒ゼツ）これがサソリの本体か
So this is Sasori's true form, huh...
（トビ）ありました！
Here it is!
ありましたよ ゼツさん！
Zetsu-san, here it is!
これで僕も
暁あかつきのメンバーに入れますかね？
I wonder if I can now become
a member of the Akatsuki...
１人分の枠 空いたんだし
One slot has opened up after all...
（黒ゼツ）バカ野郎
そんなに簡単にいくか
You idiot... It ain't that easy...
（白ゼツ）いいじゃないか
入れてあげれば
Oh come on,
why don't you just let him join...
（白ゼツ）トビは いい子だ
（トビ）あれ？
Tobi's a great kid...
ああっ
（黒ゼツ）行くぞ
Let's go.
Give me a sec, Zetsu-san!
（トビ）ちょっと待ってくださいよ
ゼツさん
確か この辺りに…
I'm sure...
It's around here somewhere.
ああ… ちょっとゼツさん！
Uh, hey, Zetsu-san!
待ってくださいよ ゼツさんってば！
Wait, please! Zetsu-san...
♪～
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forgotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenain deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
EVERDAY hereafter is a shining day.
everyday kono saki mo shining day
Unchanging singin', a bright morning smile.
kawarazu singin' hikaru asa no smile
This is the last farewell on funny days.
kore de miosame no funny days
Leaping into the future I see. Go far, dream of my heart.
tobidatsu future mezashita go far kokoro no dream of
I'll go the distance, the endless sky is blue.
i'll go the distance mihatenu sora wa blue
I've hitched a ride on the star ship, this is the best forever trip.
norikonda star ship kore ga saigo no forever trip
You are my friend.
you are my friend
Ah that day's dream...
aa ano hi no yume
You haven't forotten it, have you?
ima demo mada wasuretenai deshou
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah, it had just started your one longest way.
aa hajimatta bakka kimi no one longest way
Woah, I'm starting on a journey now!
woah ima tabidatsu yo
Thank you my friend.
thank you my friend
Ah even now,
aa ano hi no koto
I still remember that day.
ima demo mada oboeteru kara
You are my dream.
you are my dream
Ah those days that will never come back.
aa mou nidoto sou modoranai days
～♪
Woah I'll go the distance!
woah i'll go the distance
Return of the Kazekage
How much longer?
（バキ）まだか？
（砂すなの里さとの忍）まもなく見えます！
They'll be in sight soon!
あっ 我愛羅があら
Gaara...
（テマリ）あ…
That's...
（うずまきナルト）あ…
Heh... what a lavish welcome.
（カンクロウ）ヘヘ…
盛大な お出迎えじゃん
（うずまきナルト）すげえ！
Awesome...!
（ロック･リー）あんなにも
たくさんの人が！
There are so many people...!
（日向ひゅうがネジ）
さすが風影かぜかげといったところか
Just as would be expected
for the Kazekage...
（テンテン）そうね
Yeah...
（バキ）よくぞ ご無事で
I'm so glad you're safe...
（我愛羅）うん みんなのおかげだ
It's thanks to everyone...
うずまきナルト 感謝する
Uzumaki Naruto, I am truly grateful!
あ… 俺は そんな…
No, I...
I really wasn't able to do anything.
別に何もできなかったってばよ
風影様 里の者が待っております
Kazekage-sama,
the villagers are waiting for you.
さあ どうぞ
Right this way...
Well, shall we go?
じゃ 行くか
Wait.
（我愛羅）待て
（カンクロウ･ナルト）ん？
まずは…
First...
そうだな
You're right...
チヨバア様の冥福を祈り...
Let us pray that
Grandmother Chiyo's soul rests in peace.
黙とう！
A moment of silent prayer...
（エビゾウ）姉ちゃん
Nee-chan...
戻ってきたでよ
We're home...
（カンクロウ）えっ もう帰るのか？
Huh, are you leaving already?
もう少し
ゆっくりしてけばいいじゃん
You should stay a little longer...
そうだ　せめて もう１日ぐらい
That's right. At least another day...
until you've rested up.
疲れをとってからでも
そうしたいところだけど
I'd love to do that, but...
師匠… 火影ほかげ様に大至急
報告しなきゃいけないことがあって
There's something I must report to
my Mast--, the Hokage-sama, immediately...
（テマリ）そうか
I see...
（カカシ）それに暁が 砂すなの里にまで
押しかけてきたとなると
And if the Akatsuki have begun
to attack villages,
木こノ葉はの里のほうも
気になりますし
I feel uneasy being away
from the Leaf Village too.
（バキ）少しでも早く
帰りたいというわけだな
That's why you want to get back
as soon as possible, right...
Yes, that's exactly right.
（カカシ）まあ そんなところで
（バキ）しかし その体では…
But in that physical condition...
（カカシ）心配には及びません
Not to worry...
I have comrades I can rely on.
頼れる仲間がおりますから
（マイト･ガイ）おう！ 任せろ
Yeah! Leave it to me!
ところで すでにタカ丸が
第１報を運んではいるが
By the way, we have already sent
the first report out through Takamaru,
暁のメンバー２名の
生死に関しては書かれていない
but there's nothing written
as to whether the two Akatsuki members
are dead or alive...
連絡しなくていいのか？
Shouldn't you inform
your village about it?
（カカシ）直接 火影様に
報告しますよ
I'll report that directly to the Hokage.
少し気になることもあるんでね
There are other things
I'm concerned about too...
（ナルト）ん？
（シズネ）砂隠すながくれのチヨ様
１名が殉職
Chiyo-sama from the Hidden Sand
Village is the only casualty,
and the Kazekage-sama has
returned home safely.
風影様は 無事
帰還されたとのことです
ガイ班 カカシ班は
無事 任務を終了
Guy's unit and Kakashi's unit
have completed their missions.
They anticipate returning to
the Leaf Village in three days' time.
３日後には
木ノ葉に戻る予定です
All right.
（網手つなで）分かった
Uh... Tsunade-sama...
（シズネ）あの… 網手様
なんだ？
What is it?
今回の任務では
うまくいったものの
The last mission went well.
But as Jiraiya-sama stated...
自来也じらいや様の
おっしゃってたとおり
sending Naruto-kun, a Jinchuriki,
尾獣びじゅうを狙ってるヤツらのところへ
into a place where there are people
targeting the Tailed Beasts...
わざわざ人柱力じんちゅうりきであるナルト君を
送り込むのは いかがなものかと…
I question the wisdom of that...
確かに元暗部あんぶの
はたけカカシが同行しているとはいえ
It's true that former Black Ops Unit
member Kakashi is accompanying him,
なぜ このようなリスクの高い危険を
冒してまでナルト君を？
but why take such
a high risk by sending Naruto-kun?
It's for the very reason that
he's a Jinchuriki.
あいつが人柱力だからこそだ
（シズネ）あ…
人柱力を 本当に
理解してやれるのは
The only people who can
really understand Jinchuriki
人柱力のヤツだけだ
are those who are Jinchuriki themselves.
それに あいつには
不思議な力があってな
Besides... that guy has
a mysterious power...
みんな あいつに
賭けてみたくなるのさ
Everyone starts wanting
to place their bets on him.
（春野はるのサクラ）あれが？
So that's...
チヨバア様の墓だ
Grandmother Chiyo's grave.
CHIYO
She said she didn't want
a grave.
（エビゾウ）
墓などいらぬと言うとったがよ
やっぱり あったほうが
いいじゃろうと思ってな
But I thought it would
be better to have one.
こうして みんなが集まる場所も
必要だろうからよ
I felt that everyone needed
a place to gather...
（カカシ）みんな お別れを
Everybody, say your farewells...
（ガイ）うん
Okay.
Let's go.
（ガイ）行こう
Okay...
（ロック･リー）はい
（リー）サクラさん ナルト君
そろそろ出発しますよ
Sakura-san, Naruto-kun...
It's about time to depart.
Okay!
（ナルト）おう！
行くってばよ サクラちゃん
Let's go, Sakura-chan.
（サクラ）チヨバア様 ありがとう
Grandmother Chiyo, thank you...
See you...
（カンクロウ）じゃあな
Uh... yeah...
（ナルト）お… おう
Normally I suppose people
shake hands and say goodbye...
ふ… 普通なら ここで
握手とかして別れんだろうけど
but I'm not really good with
that kind of stuff, so I'll just leave it at this...
俺ってば そういうの
苦手だからな
このまま… ん？
（ナルト）ん…
フフ…
（ガイ）う～ん
（カカシ）ヘヘ…
Sensei! You guys are too slow!
（テンテン）先生たち 遅～い！
（ガイ）くっ… う～ん
Uh... I'm sorry, Guy-kun.
（カカシ）いや～ すまないね ガイ君
When I use that new Sharingan,
あの新しい写輪眼しゃりんがんを使うと
当分 体が動かなくてね ヘへ…
it takes a toll on my body
for quite a while...
Hurry!
（テンテン）早く～！
（ガイ）くっ… う～ん
（カカシ）アハ…
（ガイ）ゴホゴホ…
H-Huh... hey... wait..!
（カカシ）あっ えっ？ ちょ…
（落ちる音）
（ナルト）あ？
Huh?
What is it?
（ネジ）なんだ？
（ガイ）フフフ
（カカシ）ハハ…
（ナルト）なんかキモいってばよ
That's... kinda disgusting...
（サクラ）おっさん同士のおんぶか…
Old men giving each other
a piggyback...
That's more sickening than I imagined.
思ったより きついな
（テンテン）うわっ うざ！
Oh man... That's annoying...
おっ
そうか！ 修行ですね
I see! It's training, isn't it!
こうなったら速いぞ！
Now this way, it'll be faster!
ハアーッ！
オラ どけどけどけ～！
Move, move, move!
ハハハ～
You guys...
You think you can keep up with me?!
君たち 俺についてこられるかな？
You guys...
You think you can keep up with me?!
And when movement gets thrown in,
it's even more sickening.
（サクラ）動きが加わると
さらに きついな
- Neji...
- I refuse!
（リー）ネジ
（ネジ）断る！
（トビ）あれれ？
It looks like Deidara was done in too...
デイダラさんも
やられちゃったみたいですね
あの人 絶対
死因は爆死ですよ
There's no question that his cause
of death is from an explosion...
ね？ ゼツさん
Don't you agree, Zetsu-san?
その辺に死んでんじゃないすかね？
アハハ…
He's probably laying there dead
somewhere around there...
（デイダラ）手を離せ この野郎！
Get your hands off, you jerk...
（トビ）あ？
あっ 生きてた！
Hey! He's alive!
（黒ゼツ）人柱力は どうした？
What happened to the Jinchuriki?
俺のノルマは終わってんだろ うん
I've met my quota...
（トビ）あらら～
ぎりぎりじゃないですか デイダラさん
Oh dear, oh my...
You barely made it, Deidara-san...
大丈夫？ …じゃないか
You all right? Guess not.
（デイダラ）トビ 仏の顔も三度までだ
Tobi, even the patience of
a saint has limits...
次 なんか言ってみろ
Try saying something again and
I'll decide your cause of death myself...
てめえの死因は
俺が決めるぞ うん
（トビ）…って どうせ爆死でしょ？
No doubt it'll be death from explosion.
（黒ゼツ）それ 三度目だ
That's... past the limit...
（トビ）ぐわっ！
（トビ）くっ…
（デイダラ）窒息死だ うん
Death from suffocation!
（ダンゾウ）お前が あのカカシ班に
配属されるよう...
I've already pulled
some strings from behind...
So that you'll be posted with
Kakashi's squad.
もう手は回してある
お前は うずまきナルトと
年も さほど変わらぬうえ...
Not only are you close in age
with Uzumaki Naruto,
里の同世代の誰よりも強く
but you are also stronger than anyone
in the village of the same generation...
何よりも あのすばらしい絵心は
感嘆のひと言じゃ
And more than anything,
I admire your superb talent for painting...
本日より任務終了までの間
お前の名前は
From today until the completion
of this mission...
Your name is... Sai.
サイじゃ
（サイ）サイ… でございますね
Sai. Right...
（ダンゾウ）わしの前で
そのような作り笑いは よせ
Don't put on a fake smile
like that in front of me.
（サイ）すみません
I'm sorry...
人の心に取り入るには
まず笑顔だと教本にありました
It said in the textbook that
in order to charm people,
you first have to be able to smile.
I've been practicing, but...
練習はしているのですが
I still have difficulty in creating
facial expressions.
まだ表情というのが
うまく作れないもので…
♪～
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
It begins.
hajimare
A long, long story about you
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
"Tears", "tears".
namidatte namidatte
I want to shed them in happy times
ureshii toki ni nagashitai
So what if I want them to float in pretty puddles?
kirei na mizutamari ukabetai no wa nani
The southern sky,
minami no sora ni
It twinkles.
matataiteiru
From all of the stars meeting.
hoshi no kazu hodo no deai kara
Learning about love, receiving a map.
ai wo manandari chizu wo morattari
Are connected.
tsunagatteku
Reach for it, reach for it, far away.
todoke todoke tooku e
Now I trust these revived tears to you.
ima wo kishikaisei namida azukete
Someday a new page will turn.
itsuka mekuru peeji ni
I'm sure it'll be filled with lots of people
kitto takusan no hito ga afureru
It begins,
hajimare
～♪
A long, long story about you.
nagai nagai kimi monogatari
Next Episode
私が得た情報によると
According to information I've acquired,
Sasori is to meet with a spy he sent
to Orochimaru
サソリは10日後の お昼
草隠くさがくれにある天地橋てんちきょうで
at Tenchi Bridge in the Village Hidden
in the Grass ten days from today.
大蛇丸おろちまるの下に送り込んだスパイと
落ち合うことになっていたようです
大蛇丸への手がかりか
I see...
A clue to Orochimaru's whereabouts?
網手様 この任務
引き続き私たちにやらせてください
Tsunade-sama, please allow us
to continue on with this mission.
しかし この情報自体が
But this information itself
may be a trap to lure you in.
お前たちをおびき寄せる
わなかもしれん
かまいません
That doesn't matter.
わなならば
全力で戦うだけです！
If it is a trap,
I'll fight with all my might.
The New Target
次回
「新たなる目標」
Next time: "The New Target"
"KAZEKAGE RESCUE ARC
COMPLETION CEREMONY
THANK YOU PARTY!!!"
（網手）みんなの協力のおかげで
Thanks to everyone's cooperation,
this story arc has ended without incident.
無事 このシリーズを
終えることができた
きょうは存分に
楽しんでいってくれ！
I want you all to have fun today!
（サクラ）皆さん お疲れさまでした
Everybody, thank you for your hard work!
（カンクロウ）ああ お疲れ！
（テマリ）お疲れさま！
— Yeah, thank you!
— Thank you!
（サクラ）今回のシリーズを
終えてみて
What are your thoughts now
that this story arc is over?
皆さんの感想は いかがですか？
感想っつってもな
Thoughts, huh...
サソリにやられたあとは
ほとんど出番なかったじゃん
I hardly had any appearances
after getting beaten by Sasori.
あたしなんか
１回も戦ってないぞ
I didn't even get a chance to fight once!
蚊帳の外もいいとこだ！
I was totally left out of the loop!
大体な お前らが
いいとこ持っていきすぎなんだよ！
I mean, you guys got all the juicy parts!
（サクラ）あの ちょっと
私に そんなこと言われても…
Uh... that's really not
my responsibility, so...
（ナルト）我愛羅 お前からも
ひと言 頼むってばよ
Gaara... Put in a word on our behalf...
また借りができたな
I'm in your debt again, aren't I?
ハハッ 気にすんな
Uh, don't worry about it.
（カンクロウ）おい うずまきナルト
（ナルト）ん？
— Hey, Uzumaki Naruto!
— Huh?
次回からは お前らの倍
活躍してやるじゃん
In the next story arc, we'll have twice
the screen time as you guys!
覚悟しな！
Better prepare yourselves!
あれ？ お前ら
もう出ねえんじゃねえの？
Huh? I thought you guys weren't
appearing anymore.
（２人）は？
— Huh?
（ナルト）この先 ずっと
休みだって聞いたけど？
I heard that you're off for
an indefinite amount of time...
（２人）ふざけんな！
— Screw that!
出番よこせ
こんちきしょう
— And gimme a role, you jerk!